Hi, I'm Allison from ImagiKnit in San Francisco and I'm going to show you how to repair a dropped stitch in knitting.
A dropped stitch occurs when it slips off of the needle and then comes out through the stitch underneath it.
A drop stitch like this is a very common error.
The easiest way to fix it is to have a crochet hook handy and go ahead that through the dropped stitch.
Then go ahead and reach for the first rung on the ladder with your crochet hook, grab that and pull that through the dropped stitch.
Then repeat as you go up each rung on the ladder.
Pull it through.
We've know completed two rows worth and we've got one more to go.
We'll pull that through our loop.
And now we've got our dropped stitch here.
We want to make sure we place that back on the needle correctly.
In order to do that, the right side of the loop, versus the left side, which is here on the back, you definitely want the right side of the loop on the front of the needle because if it is placed this way it will twist your stitch, so place it this way so the right side of the loop versus the left side is on the front of the needle facing you.
Here we have repaired our dropped stitch good as new.